A Guide to the Scott Family Papers, 1777-ca. 1935
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Scott Family, Papers, 1777-ca. 1935
Library of Virginia
40079
ca. 1 cubic foot.
Scott Family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased on 15 October 2002.
Biographical Information
Ruth J. Watkins was born on 19 November 1840 and married Thomas W. Scott, son of Martha Henry Scott, on 16 November 1865. The couple resided at "Wildwood" outside Talcott in Charlotte County, Virginia. Ruth J. W. Scott died on 17 February 1894.
Scope and Content Information
Papers, 1777-ca. 1935, of the Scott family of Charlotte County, Virginia; and Pennsylvania, including almanacs, a certificate, editorials, letters including partial letters, a plat, poems, a copy of a portrait of James Lawrence (1781-1813), a church program, receipts, and an acknowledgement of Joseph B. Friend's will. Letters, 1866-1894, sent principally to Ruth J. W. Scott in Charlotte County, Virginia, are from J. Elfreth Watkins (1852-1903) in Pennsylvania, Martha Henry Scott (1814-1895), and Ruth J. W. Scott's unidentified grandmother in Norristown, Pennsylvania. They concern family matters, illnesses, J. Elfreth Watkins' education in Easton, Pennsylvania, shipments and packages exchanged, and the death of Ruth J. Scott's son Joe Morton Scott. There is also a letter, 7 August 1931, from Elizabeth V. Gaines in Saxe, Charlotte County, Virginia, to an unidentified family member concerning the Talbott family. Included with this letter were typed transcript copies of letters (enclosed), 1776-1777, from Charles Moile Talbott (1723-1779) in Philadelphia; Williamsburg, Virginia; and Wilmington, Delaware, to his parents. His letters concern Revolutionary Army training camp in Williamsburg, the death of his brother John Talbott (d. 1777), the movement of Federal troops outside Philadelphia, and battles near Wilmington, Delaware.
Arrangement
Folders arranged alphabetically; letters are separate from other material and arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Acknowledgement, 8 March 1910, attesting to the proving of Joseph B. Friend's will in Charlotte County Court., 1; 1 leaf (Folder 1)
- Farmers and Planters Almanacs, 1837-1849, 2; 4 v. (Folder 1)
- Almanac for the German Reformed Church (partial), 1866, 3; 1 v. (Folder 1)
- Certificate, 12 July 1874, issued to Martha H. Scott, Ruth J. Scott and Thomas W. Scott by the Presbyterian Church of Bethesda., 4; 1 p. (Folder 1)
- Editorials, n. d., 5; 12 p. (Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous student notes, n. d., 6; 12 p. (Folder 1)
- Plat, 4 April 1873, of three and a half acres in Charlotte County, Virginia, deeded to J. B. Friend by James E. Wood and surveyed by Thomas F. Pettus., 7; 1 leaf (Folder 1)
- Portrait (copy), n. d., of United States Navy Captain James Lawrence, (1781-1813)., 8; 1 leaf (3.75 x 4.25 inches) (Folder 1)
- Program, 4 May 1824, for the formal opening and placing of the cornerstone of the Summerville Presbyterian Church., 9; 4 p. (Folder 1)
- Receipt, 23 August 1935, issued in Denmark (?) and written in Danish (?)., 10; 1 leaf (Folder 1)
- Will inventory (?), n. d., 11; 3 leaves (Folder 1)
- Letter, 11 February 1866, sent to Ruth J. W. Scott from her grandmother in Norristown, Pennsylvania., 12; 4 p. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 21 February 1866, sent to Ruth J. W. Scott from her grandmother in Norristown, Pennsylvania., 13; 4 p. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 22 July 1866, sent to Ruth J. W. Scott from her grandmother in Norristown, Pennsylvania., 14; 4 p. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 1 October 1867, sent to Ruth J. W. Scott from her grandmother in Norristown, Pennsylvania., 15; 4 p. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 6 October 1867, sent to Ruth J. W. Scott from her brother J. Elfreth Watkins in Easton, Pennsylvania., 16; 4 p. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 5 November 1867, sent to Ruth J. W. Scott from her grandmother in Norristown, Pennsylvania., 17; 2 p. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 3 December 1867, sent to Ruth J. W. Scott from her grandmother in Norristown, Pennsylvania., 18; 2 p. (Folder 2)
- Letter, December 1867, sent to Ruth J. W. Scott from her grandmother in Norristown, Pennsylvania., 19; 2 p. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 17 February 1868, sent to Ruth J. W. Scott from her grandmother in Norristown, Pennsylvania., 20; 2 p. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 26 February 1868, sent to Ruth J. W. Scott from her grandmother in Norristown, Pennsylvania., 21; 2 p. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 2 March 1868, sent to Ruth J. W. Scott from her grandmother in Norristown, Pennsylvania., 22; 2 p. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 17 March 1868, sent to Ruth J. W. Scott from her grandmother in Norristown, Pennsylvania., 23; 2 p. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 16 April 1868, sent to Ruth J. W. Scott from her grandmother in Norristown, Pennsylvania., 24; 2 p. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 30 April 1868, sent to Ruth J. W. Scott from her grandmother in Norristown, Pennsylvania., 25; 2 p. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 10 May 1868, sent to Ruth J. W. Scott from her grandmother in Norristown, Pennsylvania., 26; 4 p. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 4 July 1868, sent to Ruth J. W. Scott from her grandmother in Norristown, Pennsylvania., 27; 2 p. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 28 July 1868, sent to Ruth J. W. Scott from her grandmother in Norristown, Pennsylvania., 28; 2 p. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 2 February 1870, sent to Ruth J. W. Scott from her brother J. Elfreth Watkins in Vincentown, New Jersey., 29; 3 p. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 24 November 1870, sent to Thomas W. Scott from his wife Ruth J. W. Scott., 30; 4 p. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 2 August 1872, sent to Ruth J. W. Scott from her mother-in-law Martha Henry Scott., 31; 2 p. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 8 December 1883, sent to Thomas W. Scott from E. E. Moffitt in North Carolina., 32; 4 p. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 7 September 1888, sent to Ella [_] from her sister., 33; 9 p. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 25 February 1894, sent to Thomas W. Scott from his brother-in-law J. Elfreth Watkins in Chicago, Illinois., 34; 4 p. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 28 February [187-], sent to Ruth J. W. Scott from her brother J. Elfreth Watkins in Easton, Pennsylvania., 35; 4 p. (Folder 2)
- Letter, n. d., sent to Ruth J. W. Scott from an undetermined author., 36; 2 p. (Folder 2)
- Letter, 7 August 1931, sent to Mary [_] from Elizabeth V. Gaines in Saxe, Charlotte County, Virginia, and including copies of Charles Moile Talbott letters, 1776-1777., 37; 19 p. (Folder 2)